Finding Aid to the Documents reflecting relations of Indians and Spaniards over tribute, wool mills, treatment of the natives, and government regulations, 1544-1608
The Bancroft Library.
Documents reflecting relations of Indians and Spaniards over tribute, wool mills, treatment of the natives, and government regulations,
1544-1608
BANC MSS M-A 7
Morelia, Mexico. Ayuntamiento.
Number of containers: 18 folders in 1 box
The Bancroft Library Berkeley, California 94720-6000
Information for Researchers
Access
Collection is open for research.
Scope and Content
These record prints are rather miscellaneous in nature as can be seen in the title. There is no indication of provenance.
Calendar of Documents
- Proceso de Francisco Madaleno (administrador) of diezmos of the bishopric for the year 1579. (Legajo 1, Doc. 7, 0001)
- Residencia of the cabildo of the city of Valladolid, taken by Luis de Valderrama, juez residencia, 1594 (Doc. 9, 0002)
- Los indios de Tarinbaro sobre daos de ciertos ganados. "Receptora.'', 1576 (Doc. 10, 0003)
- Proceso concerning a fight between a fraile and a mestizo., 1590? (Legajo 2, Doc. 10, 0004)
- Mandamiento para el alcalde mayor de Valladolid., 1581 (Doc. 15, 0005)
- Real provisin., 1587 (Doc. 17, 0006)
- Los culpados en la muerte de Venito de Valace., 1566 (Doc. 18, 0007)
- Catalina Corona vs. Alonso Larios. "Receutora.'', 1582 (Doc. 19, 0008)
- Real provision of Velasco dealing with service of Indians., 1594 (Doc. 22, 0009)
- Treatment of Indians, provision of Conde de Monterrey., 1600 (Doc. 23, 0010)
- Licencia del superior govierno..., 1567 (Libro 4, Doc. 2, 0011)
- Licencia del superior govierno..., 1562 (Doc. 3, 0012)
- Ordenanzas de Velasco. ''Para los obrajes.'', 1595 (Doc. 4, 0013)
- Real provisin., 1608 (Doc. 6, 0014)
- Carta de justicia contra Melchor Pardo., 1581 (Legajo 6, Doc. ?, 0015)
- Velasco letter., undated (Doc. 17, 0016)
- Diezmos de estancias., 1544 (Doc. 18, 0017)
- Moya letter., 1585 (Doc. 21, 0018)